<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<data version='KJV'>
	<days>
		<day date='September 1'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The fruit of the spirit is meekness.</heading>
				<text>The meek ... shall increase their joy in the Lord, and the poor among men shall rejoice in the Holy One of Israel. -Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven.  Whosoever therefore shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven. -The ornament of a meek and quiet spirit, ... is in the sight of God of great price. -Charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up.
				Follow after meekness. -Take my yoke upon you and learn of me, for I am meek and lowly in heart. -He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth: he is brought as a lamb to the slaughter, and as a sheep before her shearers is dumb so he openeth not his mouth. -Christ also suffered for us, leaving us an example, that ye should follow his steps: who did no sin neither was guile found in his mouth: who, when he was reviled reviled not again, ... but committed himself to him that judgeth righteously.</text>
				<references>Gal 5:2-23; Isa 29:19; Matt 18:3-4; 1Pet 3:4; 1Cor 13:4, 1Tim 6:11; Matt 11:29; Isa 53:7; 1Pet 2:21-23</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 2'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Wait on the Lord: be of good courage, and He shall strengthen thine heart.</heading>
				<text>Hast thou not known?  Hast thou not heard, that the everlasting God, the Lord, the Creator of the ends of the earth, fainteth not, neither is weary?  He giveth power to the faint; and to them that have no might He increaseth strength. -Fear thou not; for I am with thee: be not dismayed; for I am thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee; yea, I will uphold thee with the right hand of my righteousness. -Thou hast been a strength to the poor, a strength to the needy in his distress, a refuge from the storm, a shadow from the heat, when the blast of the terrible ones is a storm against the wall.
				The trying of your faith worketh patience.  But let patience have her perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing. -Cast not away therefore your confidence, which hath great recompence of reward.  For ye have need of patience, that after ye have done the will of God, ye might receive the promise.</text>
				<references>Ps 27:14; Isa 40:28-29; Isa 41:10; Isa 25:4; Jas 1:3-4; Heb 10:35-36</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 3'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Neither shall there be leaven seen within thee in all thy quarters</heading>
				<text>The fear of the Lord is t\o hate evil.  =Abhor that which is evil. -Abstain from all appearance of evil. -Looking diligently lest any man fail of the grace of God; lest any root of pitterness springing up trouble you, and thereby many be defiled.
				If I regard iniquity in my heart, the Lord will not hear me.
				Know ye not that a little leaven leaveneth the whole lump?  Purge out therefore the old leaven, that ye may be a new lump, as ye are unleavened.  For even Christ our passove is sacrificed for us: therefore let us keep the feast, not with old leaven,neither with the leven of malice and wickedness; but with the unleavened bread of sincerity and truth. -Let a man examine himself, and so let him eat of that bread, and drink of that cup.
				Let every one that nameth the name of Christ depart from iniquity. -Such an high priest became us, who is holy, harmless, undefiled, separate from sinners. - In him is no sin.</text>
				<references>Ex 13:7; Pr 8:18; Ro 12:9; 1Th 5:22; Heb 12:15; Ps 66:18; 1Co 5:6-8; 1Co 11:28; 2Ti 2:19; Heb 7:26; 1Jn 3:5</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The serpent said unto the woman, Ye shall not surely die: ... your eyes shall be opened, and ye shall be as gods, knowing good and evil.</heading>
				<text>I fear, lest by any means, as the serpent beguiled Eve through his subtilty so your minds should be corrupted from the simplicity that is in Christ.
                My brethren, be strong in the Lord and in the power of his might.  Put on the whole armour of God, that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil.  Take unto you the whole armour of God, that ye may be able to withstand in the evil day, and having done all, to stand.  Stand therefore, having your loins girt about with truth, and having on the breastplate of righteousness; and your feet shod with the preparation of the gospel of peace; above all, taking the shield of faith, wherewith ye shall be able to quench all the fiery darts of the wicked.  And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God. -Lest Satan should get an advantage of us: for we are not ignorant of his devices.</text>
				<references>Gen 3:4-5; 2Co 11:3; Eph 6:10-11, 13-17; 2Co 2:11</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 4'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Sit still, my daughter.</heading>
				<text>Take heed, and be quiet; fear not, neither be fainthearted. -Be still and know that I am God. - Said I not unto thee, that, if thou wouldest believe, thou sholdest see the glory of God? -The loftiness of man shall be bowed down, and the haughtiness of men shall be made low: and the LORD alone shall be exalted in that day.
                Mary ... sat at Jesus' feet, and heard his word.  Mary hath chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her. -In returning and rest shall ye be saved; in quietness and in confidence shall be your atrength. -Commune with your own heart upon your bed, and be still.
                Rest in the LORD and wait patiently for him: fret not thyself because of him who prospereth in his way, because of the man who bringeth wicked devices to pass.
                He shall not be afraid of evil tidings: his heart is fixed, trusting in the LORD.  His heart is established.
                He that believeth shall not make haste.</text>
				<references>Ruth 3:18; Isa 7:4; Ps 46:10; John 11:40; Isa 2:17; Luk 10:39,42; Isa 30:15; Ps 4:4; Ps 37:7; Ps 112:7-8; Isa 28:16</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 5'>
			<morning>
				<heading>As the body is one, and hath many members, ...so also is Christ</heading>
				<text>He is the head of the body, the church - The head over all things to the church, which is his body, the fulness of him that filleth all in all. -We are members of his body, of his flesh, and of his bones.
                A body hast thou prepared me. -Thine eyes did see my substance, yet being unperfect; and in thy book all my members were written, which in continuance were fashioned, when as yet there was none of them.
                Thine they were, and thou gavest them me. -He hath choen us in him before the foundation of the world. -Whom he did foreknow, he also did predestinate to be conformed to the image of his Son.
                Grow up into him in all things, which is the head, even Christ; from whom the whole body fitly joined together, and compacted by that which every joint supplieth, ...maketh increase of the body unto the edifying of itself in love.</text>
				<references>1Co 12:12; Col 1:18; Eph 1:22-23; Eph 5:30; Heb 10:5; Ps 139:16; Jn 17:6; Eph 1:4; Rom 8:29; Eph 4:15-16</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The fountain of living waters.</heading>
				<text>How excellent is thy lovingkindness, O God! therefore the children of men put their trust under the shadow of thy wings.  They shall be abundantly satisfied with the fatness of thy house; and thou shalt make them drink of the river of thy pleasures.  For with thee is the fountain of life.
                Thus saith the Lord God, Behold, my servants shall eat, but ye shall be hungry: behold, my servants shall drink, but ye shall be thirsty. - Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life. -This spake he of the Spirit, which they that believe on him should receive.
                Ho, every one that thirsteth, come ye to the waters. -The Spirit and the bride say, Come.  And let him that heareth say, Come.  And let him that is athirst come.  And whosoever will, let him take the water of life freely.</text>
				<references>Jer 2:13; Ps 36:7-9; Isa 65:13; Jn 4:14; Jn 7:39; Isa 55:1; Rev 22:17</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 6'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Let us lift up our heart with our hands unto God in the heavens.</heading>
				<text>Who is like unto the LORD our God, who dwelleth on high, who humbeleth himself to behold the things that are in heaven, and in the earth! -Unto thee, O LORD, do I lift up my soul. -I stretch forth my hands unto thee; my soul thirsteth after thee, as a thirsty land.  Hide not thy face from me, lest I be like unto them that go down into the pit.  Cause me to hear thy lovingkindness in the morning; for in thee do I trust: cause me to know the way wherein I should walk; for I lift up my soul unto thee.
				Because thy lovingkindness is better than life, my lips shall prase thee.  Thus will I bless thee while I live: I will lift up my hands in thy name. -Rejoice the soul of thy servant: for unto thee, O Lord, do I lift up my soul.  For thou, Lord, art good, 	and ready to forgive; and plenteous in mercy unto all them that call upon thee.
				Whatsoever ye shall ask in my name, that will I do.</text>
				<references>Lam 3:41; Ps 113:5-6; Ps 25:1; Ps 143:6-8; Ps 63:3-4; Ps 86:4-5; Jn 14:13</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Watchman, what of the night?</heading>
				<text>It is high time to awake out of sleep: for now is our salvation nearer than when we believed.  The night is far spent, the dayh is at hand: let us therefore cast off the works of darkness, and let us put on the armour of light.
				Learn a parable of the fig tree; When his branch is yet tender, and putteth forth leaves, ye know that summer is nigh: so likewise ye, when ye shall see all these things, know that it is near, even at the doors.  Heavven and earth shall pass away, but my words shall not pass away.
				I wait for the LORD, my soul doth wait, and in his word do I hope.  My soul waiteth for the Lord more than they that watch for the morning: I say, more than they that watch for the morning.
				He which testifieth these things saith, Surely, I come quickly.  Amen.  Even so, come, Lord Jesus.
				Watch, ...for ye know neither the day nor the hour wherein the Son of man cometh.</text>
				<references>Is 21:11; Ro 13:11-12; Mat 24:32-33,35; Ps 130:5-6; Rev 22:20; Mat 25:13</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 7'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Rejoicing in hope.</heading>
				<text>The hope which is laid up for you in heaven. -If in this life only we have hope in Christ, we are of all men most miserable. -We must through much tribulation enter into the kingdom of God. -Whosoever doth not bear his cross, and come after me cannot be my disciple. -No man should be moved by these afflictions, for yourselves know that we are appointed thereunto.
				Rejoice in the Lord alway: and again I say, Rejoice. -The God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, that ye may abound in hope through the power of the Holy Ghost. -Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, which according to his abundant mercy hath begotten us again unto a lively hope by the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead. -Whom having not seen, ye love; in whom though now ye see him not, yet believing, ye rejoice with joy unspeakable and full of glory. -By whom also we have access by faith into this grace wherein we stand, and rejoice in hope of the glory of God.</text>
				<references>Rom 12:12; Col 1:5; 1Co 15:19; Ac 14:22; Luk 14:27; 1Th 3:3; Php 4:4; Ro 15:13; 1Pe 1:3,8; Ro 5:2</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>I am poor and needy; yet the Lord thinketh upon me.</heading>
				<text>I know the thoughts that I think toward you, saith the Lord, thoughts of peace, and not of evil. -My thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord.  For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts.
				How precious ...are thy thoughts unto me, O God!  how great is the sum of them! If I should count them, they are more in number than the sand: when I awake, I am still with thee. -Lord, how great aare thy works!  and thy thoughts are very deep. -Many, O Lord, my God, are thy wonderful works which thou hast done, and thy thoughts which are to us-ward.
				Not many mighty, not many noble, are called. -Hath not God chosen the poor of this world rich in faith, and heirs of the kingdom? -Having nothing, and yet possessing all things. -The unsearchable riches of Christ.</text>
				<references>Ps 40:17; Jer 29:11; Isa 55:8-9; Ps 139:17-18; Ps 92:5; Ps 40:5; 1Co 1:26; Jas 2:5; 2Co 6:10; Eph 3:8</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 8'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Thou art weighed in the balances, and art found wanting.</heading>
				<text>The LORD is a God of knowledge, and by him actions are weighed. -That which is highly estgeemed among men is abomination in the sight of God. -The LORD seeth not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearance, but the LORD looketh on the heart. -Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.  For he that soweth to his flesh shall of the flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit reap life everlasting.
                What is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul? -What things were gain to me, those I counted loss for Christ.
                Behold, thou desirest truth in the inward parts. -Thou hast proved mine heart; thou hast visited me in the night; thou hast tried me, and shalt find nothing.</text>
				<references>Dan 5:27; 1Sa 2:3; Luk 16:15; 1Sa 16:7; Gal 6:7-8; Mat 16:26; Php 3:7; Ps 51:6; Ps 17:3</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Christ the firstfruits.</heading>
				<text>Except a corn of wheat fall into the ground and die, it abideth alone: but if it die, it bringeth forth much fruit. -If the firstfruit be holy the lump is also holy: and if the root be holy, so are the branches. -Now is Christ risen from the dead, and become the firstfruits of them that slept. -If we have been planted together in the likeness of his death we shall be also in the likeness of his resurrection. -The Lord Jesus Christ ...shall change our vile body, that it may be fashioned like unto his glorious body, according to the working whereby he is able even to subdue all things unto himself.
                The firstborn from the dead. -If the Spirit of him that raised up Jesus from the dead dwell in ou, he that raised up Christ from the dead shall also quicken our mortal bodies by his Spirit that dwelleth in you.
                I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.</text>
				<references>1Co 15:23; Jn 12:24; Ro 11:16; 1Co 15:20; Ro 6:5; Ph 3:20-21, Col 1:18; Ro 8:11; Jn 11:25</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 9'>
			<morning>
				<heading>He hath filled the hungry with good things; and the rich he hath send empty away.</heading>
				<text>Thou sayest, I am rich, and increased with goods, and have need of nothing; and knowest not that thou art wretched, and miserable, and poor, and blind, and naked: I counsel thee to buy of me gold tried in the fire, that thou mayest be rich.  As many as I love I rebuke and chasten: be zealous therefore, and repent.
                Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled. -When the poor and needy seek water, and there is none, and their tongue faileth for thirst, I the LORD will hear them, I the God of Israel will not forsake them. -I am the LORD thy God, ...open thy mouth wide, and I will fill it.
                Wherefore do ye spend money for that which is not bread? and your labour for that which satisfieth not? hearken diligently unto me, and eat ye that which is good, and let your soul delight itself in fatness. -I am the bread of life: he that cometh to me shall never hunger; and he that believeth on me shall never thirst.</text>
				<references>Luk 1:53; Re 3:17-19; Mt 5:6; Is 41:17; Ps 81:10; Is 55:2; Jn 6:35</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>My feet were almost gone; my steps had well nigh slipped.</heading>
				<text>When I said, My foot slippeth; thy mercy, O Lord, held me up.
				The Lord said, Simon, Simon, behold Satan hath desired to have you, that he may sift you as wheat: but I have prayed for thee, that thy faith fail not.
				A just man falleth seven times, and riseth up again. -Although he fall, he shall not be utterly cast down: for the Lord upholdeth him with his hand.
				Rejoice not against me, O my enemy: when I fall, I shall arise: when I sit in darkness, the Lord shall be a light unto me. -He shall deliver thee in six troubles: yea, in seven there shall no evil touch thee.
				If any man sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous. -Wherefore he is able also to save them to the uttermost that come unto God by him, seeing he ever liveth to make intercession for them.</text>
				<references>Ps 73:2; Ps 94:18; Lk 22:31-32; Pr 24:16; Ps 37:24; Mic 7:8; Job 5:19; 1Jn 2:1; Heb 7:25</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 10'>
			<morning>
				<heading>I will give them one heart, and one way, that they may fear me for ever, for the good of them, and of their children after them.</heading>
				<text>A new heart ...will I give you, and a new spirit will I put within you. -Good and upright is the LORD: therefore will he teach sinners in the way.  The meek will he guide in judgement: and the meek will he teach his way.  All the paths of the LORD are mercy and truth unto such as keep his covenant and his testimonies.
                That they all may be one; as thou, Father, art in me, and I in thee, that they also may be one in us: that the world may believe that thou hast sent me.
                I ...beseech you that ye walk worthy of the vocation wherewith ye are called, with all lowliness and meekness, ...endeavouring to keep the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace.  There is one body, and one Spirit, even as ye are called in one hope of your calling; one Lord, one faith, one baptism, one God and Father of all, who is above all, and through all, and in you all.</text>
				<references>Jer 32:39; Ez 36:26; Ps 25:8-10; Jn 17:21; Eph 4:1-6</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>They that wait upon the Lord shall renew their strength. (Or, change strength.)</heading>
				<text>When I am weak, then am I strong. -MyGod shall be my strength. -He said unto me, My grace is sufficient for thee: for my strength is made perfect in weakness.  Most gladly therefore will I rather glory in my infirmities, that the power of Christ may rest upon me. -Let him take hold of my strength.
                Cast thy burden upon the LORD, and he shall sustain thee. -The arms of his hands were made strong by the hands of the mighty God of Jacob.
                I will not let thee go, except thou bless me.
                Thou comest to me with a sword, and with a spear, and with a shield: but I come to thee in the name of the LORD of hosts, the God of the armies of Israel, whom thou hast defied. -Plead my cause, O LORD, with them that strive with me: fight against them that fight against me.  Take hold of shield and buckler, and stand up for mine help.</text>
				<references>Is 40:31; 2Co12:10; Is 49:5; 2Co 12:9; Is 27:5; Ps 55:22; Ge 49:24; Ge 32:26; 1Sa 17:45; Ps 35:1-2</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 11'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Be not conformed to this world: but be ye transformed by the renewing of your mind.</heading>
				<text>Thou shalt not follow a multitude to do evil.
                Know ye not that the friendship of the world is enmity with God?  whosoever therefore will be a friend of the world is the enemy of God.
                What fellowship hath righteousness with unrighteusness?  and what communion hath light with darknewss?  And what concord hath Christ with Belial?  or what part hath he that believeth with an infidel?  And what agreement hath the temple of God with idols? -Love not the world, neither the things that are in the world.  If any man love the world, the love of the Father is not in him.  The world passeth away, and the lust thereof: but he that doeth the will of God abideth for ever.
                In time past ye walked according to the course of this world, according to the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that now worketh in the children of disobedience. -Ye have not so learned Christ; if so be that ye have heard him, ...as the truth is in Jesus.</text>
				<references>Ro 12:2; Ex 23:2; Ja 4:4; 2Co 6:14-16; 1Jn 2:15,17; Ep 2:2; Ep 4:20-21</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Man goeth forth unto his work and to his labour until the evening.</heading>
				<text>In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread, till thou return unto the ground. -We commanded you, that if any would not work, neither should he eat. Study to be quiet, and to do your own business, and to work with your own hands.
                Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it with thy might; for there is no work, nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom, in the grave, whither thou goest. -The night cometh when no man can work.
                Let us not be weary in well doing: for in due season we shall reap, if we faint not. -Always abounding in the work of the Lord, forasmuch as ye know that your labour is not in vain in the Lord.
                There remaineth ...a rest to the people of God. -Unto us, which have borne the burden and heat of the day. -This is the rest wherewith ye may cause the weary to rest; and this is the refreshing</text>
				<references>Ps 104:23; Ge 3:19; 2Th 3:10; 1Th 4:11; Ec 9:10; Jn 9:4; Ga 6:9; 1Co 15:58; He 4:9; Mat 20:12; Is 28:12</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 12'>
			<morning>
				<heading>I have seen his ways and will heal him.</heading>
				<text>I am the LORD that healeth thee.
                O LORD, thou hast searched me, and known me.  Thou knowest my downsitting and mine uprising, thou understandest my thought afar off.  Thou compassest my path and my lying down, and art acquainted with all my ways. - Thou hast set our iniquities before thee, our secret sins in the light of thy countenance. -All things are naked and opened unto the eyes of him with whom we have to do.
                Come now, and let us reason together, saith the LORD: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool. -He is gracious unto him, and saith, Deliver him from going down to the pit: I have found a ransom. -He was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities: the chastisement of our peace was upon hom; and with his stripes we are healed. -He hath sent me to bind up the brokenhearted. -Thy faith hath made thee whole; go in peace, and be whole of thy plague.</text>
				<references>Is57:18; Ex 15:26; Ps 139:1-3; Ps 90:8; He 4:13; Is 1:18; Job 33:24; Is 53:5; Is 61:1; Mar 5:34</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The Lord taketh my part.</heading>
				<text>The LORD hear thee in the day of trouble; the name of the God of Jacob defend thee; send thee help from the sanctuary, and strengthen thee out of Zion.  We will rejoice in thy salvation, and in the name of our God we will set up our banners.  Some trust in chariots, and some in horses: but we will remember the name of the LORD our God.  They are brought down and fallen: but we are risen, and stand upright.
					When the enemy shall come in like a flood, the Spirit of the LORD shall lift up a standard against him. -There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God is faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able: but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it.
					If God be for us, who can be against us? -The LORD is on my side; I will not fear.
					Our God whom we serve is able to deliver us, and he will deliver us.</text>
				<references>Ps 118:7; Ps 20:1,2,5,7,8; Isa 59:19; 1Co 10:13; Rom 8:31; Ps 118:6; Dan 3:17</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 13'>
			<morning>
				<heading>If any man thirst, let him come unto me, and drink.</heading>
				<text>My soul longeth, yea, even fainteth for the courts of the LORD: my heart and my flesh crieth out for the living God. -O God, thou art my God; early will I seek thee: my soul thirsteth for thee, my flesh longeth for thee in a dry and thirsty land, where no water is; To see thy power and thy glory, so as I have seen thee in the sanctuary.
                Ho, every one that thirsteth, come ye to the waters, and he that hat no money; come ye, buy, and eat; yea, come, buy wine and milk without money and without price. -The Spirit and the bride say, Come. And let him that heareth say, Come.  And let him that is athirst come.  And whosoever will, let him take the water of life freely. -Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life. -My blood is drink indeed.
                Eat, O friends; drink, yea, drink abundantly, O beloved.</text>
				<references>Jn 7:37; Ps 84:2; Ps 63:1-2; Is 55:1; Re 22:17; Jn 4:14; Jn 6:55; Ca 5:1</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Ye are the salt of the earth.</heading>
				<text>That which is not corruptible. -Being born again, not of corruptible seed, but of incorruptible, by the word of God, which liveth and abideth for ever. -He that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live. -The children of God, being the children of the resurrection. -The uncorruptible God.
					If any man have not the Spirit of Christ, he is none of his. And if Christ be in you, the body is dead because of sin; but the Spirit is life because of righteousness.  But if the Spirit of him that raised up Jesus from the dead dwell in you, he that raised up Christ from the dead shall also quicken your mortal bodies by his Spirit that dwelleth in you. -It is sown in corruption; it is raised in incorruption.
					Have salt in yourselves, and have peace one with another. -Let no corrupt communication proceed out of your mouth, but that which is good to the use of edifying, that it may minister grace unto the hearers.</text>
				<references>Mt 5:13; 1Pe 3:4; 1Pe 1:23; Jn 11:25; Lk 20:36; Ro 1:23; Ro 5:9-11; 1Co 15:42; Mk 9:50; Eph 4:29</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 14'>
			<morning>
				<heading>I, even I, am he that comforteth you.</heading>
				<text>Blessed be God, even the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies, and the God of all comfort; who comforteth us in all our tribulation, that we may be able to comfort them which are in any trouble, by the comfort wherewith we ourselves are comforted of God. -Like as a father pitieth his children, so the LORD pitieth them that fear him.  For he knoweth our frame; he remembereth that we are dust. -As one whom his mother comforteth, so will I comfort you. -Casting all your care upon him, for he careth for you.
                Thou, O Lord, art a God full of compassion, and gracious, longsuffering, and plenteous in mercy and truth.
                Another Comforter ...even the Spirit of truth. -The Spirit ...helpeth our infirmities.
                God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more death, neitgher sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away.</text>
				<references>Is 51:12; 2Co 1:3-4; Ps 103:13-14; Is 66:13; 1Pe 5:7; Ps 86:15; Jn 14:16-17; Ro 8:26; Re 21:4</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Ye were called unto the fellowship of his Son.</heading>
				<text>He received from God the Father honour and glory, when there came such a voice to him from the excelleng glory, This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased. -Behold, what manner of love the Father hath bestowed upon us, that we should be called the sons of God.
					Be ye ...followers of God, as dear children. -If children, then heirs; heirs of God, and joint heirs with Christ.
					The brightness of his glory, and the express image of his person. -Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.
					Jesus the author and finisher of our faith; who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame. -These things I speak in the world, that they might have my joy fulfilled in themselves. -As the sufferings of Christ abound in us, so our consolation also aboundeth by Christ.</text>
				<references>1Co 1:9; 2Pe 1:17; 1Jn 3:1; Eph 5:1; Ro 8:17; Heb 1:3; Mt 5:16; Heb 12:2; Jn 17:13; 2Co 1:5</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 15'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Sin shall not have dominion over you: for ye are not under the law, but under grace.</heading>
				<text>What the?  Shall we sin, because we are not under the law, but under Grace?  God forbid. -My brethren, ye ...are become dead to the law by the body of Christ; that ye should be married to another, even to him who is raised from the dead, that we should bring forth fruit unto God. -Being not without law to God, but under the law to Christ. -The sting of death is sin; and the strength of sin is the law.   But thanks be to God, which giveth us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.
                The law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus hath made me free from the law of sin and death. -Whosoever committeth sin is the servant of sin.  If the Son ...shall make you free, ye shall be free indeed.
                Stand fast therefore in the liberty wherewith Christ hath made us free, and be not entangled again with the yoke of bondage.</text>
				<references>Ro 6:14-15; Ro 7:4; 1Co 9:21; 1Co 15:56-57; Ro 8:2; Jn 8:34,36; Ga 5:1</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>A double minded man is unstable in all his ways.</heading>
				<text>No man, having put his hand to the plough and looking back, is fit for the kingdom of God.
					He that cometh to God must believe that he is, and that he is a rewarder of them that diligently seek him. -Let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.  For let not that man think that he shall receive anything of the Lord. -What things soever ye desire when ye pray, believe that ye receive them, and ye shall have them.
					Be no more children, tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine, by the sleight of men, and cunning craftiness, whereby they lie in wait to deceive: but speaking the truth in love, ...grow up into him in all things which is the head, even Christ.
					Abide in me. -Be ye steadfast, unmoveable, always abounding in the work of the Lord, forasmuch as ye know that your labour is not in voin in the Lord.</text>
				<references>Jas 1:8; Lk 9:62; Heb 11:6; Jas 1:6-7; Mk 11:24; Eph 4:14-15; Jn 15:4; 1Co 15:58</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 16'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The Lord pondereth the hearts.</heading>
				<text>The LORD knoweth the way of the righteous: but the way of the ungodly shall perish. -The LORD will shep who are his, and who is holy. -Thy Father which seeth in secret himself shall reward thee openly.
                Search me, O God, and know my heart: try me, and know my thoughts: and see if there be any wicked way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting. -There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear.
                Lord, all my desire is before thee; and my groaning is not hid from thee. -When my spirit was overwhelmed within me, then thou knewest my path. -He that searcheth the hearts knoweth what is the mind of the Spirit, because he maketh intercession for the saints according to the will of God.
                The foundation of God standeth sure, having this seal, The Lord knoweth them that are his.  And, Le t every one that nameth the name of Christ depart from iniquity.</text>
				<references>Pr 21:2; Ps 1:6; Nu 16:5; Mt 6:4; Ps 139:23-24; 1Jn 4:18; Ps 38:9; Ps 142:3; Ro 8:27; 2Ti 2:19</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning.</heading>
				<text>No man should be moved by these afflictions: for yourselves know that we are appointed thereunto.  For verily, when we were with you, we told you before that we should suffer tribulation. -In me ye ...have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.
					I shall be satisfied, when I awake, with thy likeness. -The night is far spent, the day is at hand. -He shall be as the light of the morning, when the sun riseth, even a morning without clouds; as the tender grass springing out of the earth by clear shining after rain.
					He will swallow up death in victory; and the Lord GOD will wipe away tears form off all faces. -There shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away. -We which are alive and remain shall be caught up together with them in the clouds, to meet the Lord in the air.  Wherefore comfort one another with these words.</text>
				<references>Ps 30:5; 1Th 3:3-4; Jn 16:33; Ps 17:15; Ro 13:12; 2Sa 23:4; Is 25:8; Rev 21:4; 1Th 4:17-18</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 17'>
			<morning>
				<heading>A bruised reed shall he not break.</heading>
				<text>The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit: a broken and a contrite heart O God, thou wilt not despise. -He healeth the broken in heart, and bindeth up their wounds. -Thus saith the high and lofty One that inhabiteth eternity, whose name is Holy; I dwell in the high and holy place, with him also that is of a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of the humble, and to revive the heart of the contrite ones.  For I will not contend for ever, neither will I be always roth: for the spirit should fail before me, and the souls which I have made.
                 I will seek that which was lost, and bring again that which was driven away, and will bind up that which was broken, and will strengthen that which was sick. [Wherefore lift up the hands which hang down, and the feeble knees; and make straight paths for your feet, lest that which is lame be turned out of the way; but let it rather be healed. -Behold, your God ...will come and save you.</text>
				<references>Mt 12:20; Ps 51:17; Ps 147:3; Is 57:15-16; Ez 34:16; He 12:12-13; Is 35:4</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>O taste and see that the Lord is good: blessed is the man that trusteth in him.</heading>
				<text>When the ruler of the feast had tasted the water that was made wine, and knew not whence it was: he saith, ...Every man at the beginning doth set forth good wine; and when men have well drunk, then that which is worse: but thou hast kept the good wine until now.
                The ear trieth words, as the mouth tasteth meat. -I believed, and therefore have I spoken. -I know whom I have believed. -I sat down under his shadow with great delight, and his fruit was sweet to my taste.
                The goodness of God. -He that spared not his own Son, but deliverd him up for us all, how shall he not with him also freely give us all things?
                As newborn babes, desire the sincere mild of the word, that ye may grow thereby: if so be ye have tasted that the Lord is gracious.
                Let all those that put their trust in thee rejoice:  let them ever shout for joy.</text>
				<references>Ps 34:8; Jn 2:9-10; Job 34:3; 2Co 4:13; 2Ti 1:12; Ca 2:3 Ro 2:4; Ro 8:32; 1Pe 2:2-3 Ps 5-11</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='September 18'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Open thou mine eyes, that I may behold wondrous things out of thy law.</heading>
				<text>Then opened he their understanding, that they might understand the scriptures. -It is given unto you to know the mysteries of the kingdom of heaven, but to them it is not give. -I thank thee, O Father, Lord of heaven and earth, because thou hast hid these things from the wise and prudent, and hast revealed them to babes.  Even so, Father: for so it seemed good in thy sight. -We have received, not the spirit of the world, but the spirit which is of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God. -How precious also are thy thoughts unto me, O God! how great is the sum of them!  If I should count them, they are more in number than the sand. O the depth of the riches both of the wisdom and knowledge of God! how unsearchable are his judgements, and his ways past finding out!  For who hath known the mind of the Lord? or who hath been his counsellor? For of him, and through him, and to him are all things: to whom be glory for ever. Amen.</text>
				<references>Ps 119:18; Lk 24:45; Mt 13:11; Mt 11:25-26; 1Co 2:12; Ps 139:17-18; Ro 11:33-34,46</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>En Hakkore. (or, The well of him that cride.)</heading>
				<text>If thou knewest the gift of God, and who it is that saith to thee, Give me to drink; thou wouldest have asked of him, and he would have given thee living water. -If any man thirst, let him come unto me and drink.  Thes spake he of the Spirit, which they that believe on him should receive.
                Prove me now herewith, saith the LORD of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heave, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it. -If ye, ...being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children: how much more shall your heavenly Father give the Holy Spirit to them that ask him? -Ask and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find.
                Because ye are sons, God hat sent forth the Spirit of his Son into your hearts, crying, Abba, Father. -Ye have not received the spirit of bondage again to fear; but ye have received the Spirit of adoption, whereby we cry, Abba, Father.</text>
				<references>Jdg 15:19; Jn 4:10; Jn 7:37,39; Mal 3:10; Lk 11:13; Lk 11:9; Gal 4:6; Ro 8:15</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 19'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The God of all grace.</heading>
				<text>I will proclaim the name of the LORD before thee; and will be gracious to whom I will be gracious. -He is gracious unto him, and saith, Deliver him from going down to the pit; I have found a ransom. -Being justified freely by his grace, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus: whom God hath set forth to be a propitiation through faith in his blood, to declare his righteousness for the remission of sins that are past, through the forbearance of God. -Grace and truth came by Jesus Christ.
                By grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God. -Grace, mercy, and peace from God our Father and Jesus Christ our Lord. -Unto every one of us is given grace according to the measure of the gift of Christ. -As every man hath received the gift, even so minister the same one to another, as good stewards of the manifold grace of God. -He giveth more grace.
                Grow in grace, and in the knowledge of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ.  To him be glory both now and for ever.</text>
				<references>1Pe5:10; Ex 33:19; Job 33:24; Ro 3:24-25; Jn 1:17 Ep 2:8; 1Ti 1:2; Ep 4:7; 1Pe 4:10; Jas 4:6; 2Pe 3:18</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>I will lift up mine eyes unto the hills, from whence cometh my help.  My help cometh from the Lord.</heading>
				<text>As the mountains are round about Jerusalem, so the LORD is round about his people from henceforth even for ever.
                Unto thee lift I up mine eyes, O thou that dwellest in the heavens.  Behold, as the eyes of servants look unto the hand of their masters, and as the eyes of a maiden unto the hand of her mistress; so our eyes wait upon the LORD our God, until that he have mercy upon us. -Because thou hast been my help, therefore in the shadow of thy wings will I rejoice.
                O our God, wilt thou not judge them? for we have no might against this great company that cometh against us; neither know we what to do: but our eyes are upon thee. -Mine eyes are ever toward the LORD; for he shall pluck my feet out of the net. -Our help is in the name of the LORD, who made heaven and earth.</text>
				<references>Ps 121:1-2; Ps 125:2; Ps 123:1-2; Ps 63:7; 1Ch 20:12; Ps 25:15; Ps 124:8</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 20'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Happy is the man that findeth wisdom, and the man that getteth understanding.</heading>
				<text>Whoso findeth me findeth life, and shall obtain favour of the LORD.
                Thus saith the LORD, Let not the wise man glory in his wisdom, neither let the mighty man glory in ihis might: ...but let him that glorieth glory in this, that he understandeth and knoweth me, that I am the LORD. -The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom.
                What things were gain to me, those I counted loss for Christ. Yea doubtless and I count all things but loss for the excellency of the knoowledge of Christ Jesus my Lord: for whom I have suffered the loss of all things, and do count them but dung, that I may win Christ. -In whom are hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge. -Counsel is mine, and sound wisdom: I am understanding; I have strength.
                Christ Jesus, ...is made unto us wisdom, and righteousness, and sanctification, and redemption.
                He that winneth souls is wise.</text>
				<references>Pr 3:13; Pr 8:35; Je 9:23-24; Pr 9:10; Php 3:7-8; Col 2:3; Pr 8:14; 1Co 1:30; Pr 11:30</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Poor, yet making many rich.</heading>
				<text>Ye know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that, though he was rich, yet for your sakes he became poor, that ye through his poverty might be rich. -Of his fulness have all we received, and grace for grace. -My God shall supply all your need according to his riches in glory by Christ Jesus. - God is able to make all grace abound toward you; that ye, always having all sufficiency in all things, may abound to every good work.
					Hath not God chosen the poor of this world rich in faith, and heirs of the kingdom which he hath promised to them that love him? -Not many wise men after the flesh, not many mighty, not many noble, are called: but God hath chosen the foolish things of the world to confound the wise; and God hath chosen the weak things of the world to confound the things which are mighty.
					We have this treasure in earthen vessels, that the excellency of the power may be of God, and not of us.</text>
				<references>2Co 6:10; 2Co 8:9; Jn 1:16; Php 4:19; 2Co 9:8; Jas 2:5; 1Co 1:26-27; 2Co 4:7</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 21'>
			<morning>
				<heading>We know that all things work together for good to them that love God.</heading>
				<text>Surely the wrath of man shall praise thee: the remainder of wrath shalt thou restrain. -Ye thought evil against me: but God meant it unto good.
                All things are yours; whether ...the world, or life or death or things present, or things to come; all are yours; and ye are Christ's; and Christ is God's. -All things are for your sakes, that the abundant grace might through the thanksgiving of many redound to the glory of God.  For which cause we faint not; but though our outward man perish, yet the inward man is renewed day by day.  For our light affliction, which is but for a moment, worketh for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory.
                My brethren, count it all joy when ye fall into divers temptations; knowing this, that the trying of your faith worketh patience.  But let patience have her perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing.</text>
				<references>Ro 8:28; Ps 76:10; Ge 50:20; 1Co 3:21-23; 2Co 4:15-17; Ja 1:2-4</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The communion of the Holy Ghost be with you all.</heading>
				<text>I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another Conforter, that he may abide with you for ever; even the Spirit of truth; whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him not, neither knoweth him: but ye know him; for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you. -He shall not speak of himself.  He shall glorify me: for he shall receive of mine, and shall shew it unto you.
					The love of God is shed abroad in our hearts by teh Holy Ghost which is given to us.
					He that is joined unto the Lord is one spirit. -Know ye not that your body is the tmple of the Holy Ghost which is in you, which ye have of God, and ye are not your own?
					Grieve not the holy Spirit of God, whereby ye are sealed unto the day of redemption. -The Spirit also helpeth our infirmities: for we know not what we would pray for as we ought: but the Spirit itself maketh intercession for us with groanings which cannot be uttered.</text>
				<references>2Co 13:14; Jn 14:16-17; Jn 16:13-14; Ro 5:5; 1Co 6:17; 1Co 6:19; Eph 4:30; Ro 8:26</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 22'>
			<morning>
				<heading>My meditation of him shall be sweet: I will be glad in the Lord.</heading>
				<text>As the apple tree among the trees of the wood, so is my deloved among the sons.  I sat down under his shadow with great delight, and his fruit was sweet to my taste. -For who in the heaven can be compared unto the LORD? who among. the sons of the mighty can be likened unto the LORD?
                My beloved is white and ruddy, the chiefest among ten thousand. -One pearl of great price. -The prince of the kings of the earth.
                His head is as the most fine gold, his locks are bushy, and black as a raven. -The head over all things. -He is the head of the body, the church.
                His cheeks are as a bed of spices, as sweet flowers. -He could not be hid.
                His lips like lilies, dropping sweet smelling myrrh. -Never man spake like this man.
                His countenance is as Lebanon, excellent as the cedars. -Make thy face to shine upon thy servant. -LORD, lift thou up the light of thy countenance upon us.</text>
				<references>Ps 104:34; Ca 2:3; Ps 89:6; Ca 5:10; Mt 13:46; Rev 1:5; Ca 5:11; Eph 1:22; Col 1:18; Ca 5:13; Mk 7:24; Ca 5:13; Jn 7:46; Ca 5:15; Ps 31:16; Ps 4:6</references>
            </morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>O my Father, if it be possible, let this coup pass from me: nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt.</heading>
				<text>Now is my soul troubled; and what shall I say? Father, save me from this hour: but for this cause came I unto this hour.
					I came down from heaven, not to do mine own will, but the will of him that sent me. -He ...became obedient unto death, even the death of the cross. -In the days of his flesh, when he had offered up prayers and supplications iwth strong crying and tears unto him that was able to save him from death, and was heard in that he feared; though he were a Son, yet learned he obedience by the things which he suffered.
					Thinkest thou that I cannot now pray to my Father, and he shall presently give me more than twelve legions of angels? -Thus it is written, and thus it behooved Christ to suffer, and to ruse from the dead the third day: and that repentance and remission of sins should be preached in his name among all nations. beginning at Jerusalem.</text>
				<references>Mt 26:39; Jn 12:27; Jn 6:38; Php 2:8; Heb 5:7-8; Mt 26:53; Lk 24:46-47</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 23'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Our God hath not forsaken us</heading>
				<text>Beloved, think it not strange concerning the fiery trial which is to try you, as though some strange thing happened unto you. -If ye endure chastening, God dealeth with you as with sons; for what son is he whom the father chasteneth not? But if ye be without chastisement, whereof all are partakers, then are ye bastards, and not sons.
                The LORD your God proveth you, to know whether ye love the LORD your God with all your heart and with all your soul.
                The LORD will not forsake his people for his great name's sake: because it hath pleased the LORD to make you his people. -Can a woman forget her sucking child, that she should not have compassion on the son of her womb? yea, they may forget, yet will I not forget thee. -Happy is he that hath the God of Jacob for his help, whose hope is in the LORD his God.</text>
            	<references>Ez 9:9; 1Pe 4:12; Heb 12:7-8; Dt 13:3; 1Sa 12:22; Isa 49:15; Ps 146:5; Lk 18:7-8</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>He that overcometh shall inherit all things.</heading>
				<text>If in this life only we have hope in Christ, we are of all men most miserable. -Now they desire a better country, that is, an heavenly: wherefore God is not ashamed to be called their God; for he hath prepared for them a city. -An inheritance incorruptible, and undefiled, and that fadeth not away, reserved in heaven for you.
                All things are your's; ...the world, or life, or death, or things present, or things to come; all are your's. -Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.  But God hath revealed them unto us by his Spirit.
                Look to yourselves, that we lose not those things which we have wrought, but that we receive a full reward. -Let us lay aside every weight, and the sin which doth so easily beset us, and let us run with patience the race that is set before us.</text>
            	<references>Rev 21:7; 1Co 15:19; Heb 11:16; 1Pe 1:4; 1Co 3:21-22; 1Co 2:9-10; 2Jn 8; Heb 2:1</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 24'>
			<morning>
				<heading>It is good for me to draw near to God.</heading>
				<text>Lord, I have loved the habitation of thy house, and the place where thine honour dwelleth. -A day in thy courts is better than a thousand.  I had rather be a door-keeper in the house of my God, than to dwell in the tents of wickedness. -Blessed is the man whom thou choosest, and causest to approach unto thee, that he may dwell in thy courts: we shall be satisfied with the goodness of thy house, even of thy holy temple.
                The Lord is good unto them that wait for him, to the soul that seeketh him. -Therefore will the Lord wait that he may be gracious unto you, and therefore will he be exalted that he may have mercy upon you: for the Lord is a God of Judgment: blessed are all they that wait for him.
                Having therefore, brethren, boldness to enter into the holiest by the blood of Jesus, by a new and living way, which he hath consecrated for us: ...let us draw newara with a true heart in full assurance of faith, having our hearts sprinkeld from an evil conscience.</text>
				<references>Ps 73:28; Ps 26:8; Ps 84:10; Ps 65:4; Lam 3:25; Isa 30:18; Heb 10:19-20,22</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 25'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Let patience have her perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing.</heading>
				<text>Now for a season, if need be, ye are in heaviness through manifold temptations: that the trial of your faith, being much more precious than of gold that perisheth, though it be tried with fire, might be found unto praise and honour and glory at the appearing of Jesus Christ. -We glory in tribulations: ...knowing that tribulation worketh patience; and patience, experience; and experience, hope.
					It is good that a man should both hope and quietly wait for the salvation of the LORD. -Ye have in heaven a better and an enduring substance. Cast not away therefore your confidence, which hath great recompence of reward.  For ye have need of patience, that, after ye have done the will of God, ye might receive the promise. -Our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God, even our Father, which hath loved us, and hath given us everlasting consolation and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts.</text>
				<references>Jas 1:4; 1Pe 1:6-7; Ro 5:3-4; Lam 3:26; Heb 10:34-36; 2Th 2:16-17</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 26'>
			<morning>
				<heading>A God of truth and without iniquity, just and right is he.</heading>
				<text>Him that judgeth righteously. -We must all appear before the judgment seat of Christ; that every one may receive the things done in his body, according to that he hath done, whether it be good or bad. -Every one of us shall give account of himself to God. -The soul that sinneth it shall die.
				Awake, O sword, against my shepherd, and against the man that is my fellow, saith the LORD of hosts: smite the shepherd. -The LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all. -Mercy and truth are met together: righteousness and peace have kissed each other. -Mercy rejoiceth against judgment. -The wages of sin is death; but the gift of God is eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.
				A just God and Saviour; there is none beside me. -Just, and the justifier of him which believeth in Jesus. -Justified freely by his grace through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus.</text>
				<references>Dt 32:4; 1Pe 2:23; 2Co 5:10; Ro 14:12: Eze 18:4; Zec 13:7; Isa 53:6; Ps 85:10; Is 2:13; Ro 6:23; Is 45:21; Ro 3:26; Ro 3:24</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Death is swallowed up in victory.</heading>
				<text>Thanks be to God, which giveth us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.
					Forasmuch ...as the children are partakers of flesh and blood, he also himself likewise took part of the same; that through death he might destroy him that had the power of death, that is, the devil; and deliver them who through fear of death were all their lifetime subject to bondage.
					If we be dead with Christ, we believe that we also live with hom: knowing that Christ being raised from the dead dieth no more; death hath no more dominion over him.  For in that he died, he died unto sin once: but in that he liveth, he liveth unto God.
					Likewise reckon ye also yourselves to be dead indeed unto sin, but alive unto God through Jesus Christ our Lord.
					In all these things we are more than conquerors through him that loved us.</text>
				<references>1Co 15:54; 1Co 15:57; He 2:14-15; Rom 6:8-10; Ro 6:11; Ro 8:37</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 27'>
			<morning>
				<heading>They shall put my name upon the children of Israel; and I will bless them.</heading>
				<text>O LORD our God, other lords beside thee have had dominion over us: but by thee only will we make mention of thy name. -We are thine: thou never barest rule over them; they were not called by thy name.
					All people of the earth shall see that thou art called by the name of the LORD; and they shall be afraid of thee. -The LORD will not forsake his people for his great name's sake: because it hath pleased the LORD to make you his people.
					O Lord, hear; O Lord, forgive; O Lord, hearken and do; defer not, for thine own sake, O my God: for thy city and thy people are called by thy name. -Help us, O God of our salvation, for the glory of thy name: and deliver us, and purge away our sins, for thy name's sake. Wherefore should the heathen say, Where is their God? -The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous runneth into it and is safe.</text>
				<references>Nu 6:27; Is 26:13; Is 63:19; Dt 28:10; 1Sa 12:22; Dan 9:19; Ps 79:9-10; Pr 18:10</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The heavens declare the glory of Fod; and the firmament sheweth his handywork.</heading>
				<text>The invisible things of him from the creation of the world are clearly seen, being understood by the things that are made, even his eternal power and Godhead. -He left not himself without witness. -Day unto day uttereth speech, and night unto night sheweth knowledge.  There is no speech no language, where their voice is not heard.
					When I consider thy heavens, the work of thy fingers, the moon and the stars, which thou hast ordained; what is man, that thou art mindful of him? and the son of man, that thou visitest him?
					There is one glory of the sun, and another glory of the moon, and another glory of the stars: for one star differeth from another star in glory.  So also is the resurrection of the dead. -They that be wise shall shine as the brightness of the firmament; and they that turn many to righteousness as the stars for ever and ever.</text>
				<references>Ps 19:1; Ro 1:20; Ac 14:17; Ps 19:2-3; 1Co 15:41; Dan 12:3</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 28'>
			<morning>
				<heading>They shall put my name upon the children of Israel; and I will bless them</heading>
				<text>O Lord our God, other lords beside thee have had dominion over us: but by thee only will we make mention of thy name. -We are thine: thou never barest rule over them; they were not called by thy name.
                All people of the earth shall see that thou art called by the name of the LORD; and they shall be afraid of thee. -The LORD will not forsake his people for his great name's sake: because it hath pleased the LORD to make you his people.
                O Lord, hear; O Lord, forgive; O Lord, hearken and do; defer not, for thine own sake, O my God: for thy city and thy people are called by thy name. -Help us, O God of our salvation, for the glory of thy name: and deliver us, and purge away our sins, for thy name's sake. Wherefore should the heathen say, Where is their God? -The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous runneth into it, and is safe.</text>
				<references>Nu 6:27; Is 26:13; Is 63:19; Dt 28:10; 1Sa 12:22; Da 9:19; Ps 79:9-10;Pr18:10</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 29'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Hereby perceive we the love of God, because he laid down his life for us.</heading>
				<text>The love of Christ, which passeth knowledge. -Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.  Ye know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that, though he was rich, yet for your sakes he became poor, that ye through his poverty might be rich. -Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought also to love one another. -Be ye kind one to another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another even as God for Christ's sake hath forgiven you. -Forbearing one another, and forgiving one another, if any man have a quarrel against any: even as Christ forgave you, so also do ye. -For even the Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister, and to give his life a ransom for many. -Christ ...suffered for us, leaving us an example that ye should follow his steps.
                Ye also ought to wash one another's feet. For I have given you an example, that ye should do as I have done to you. -We ought to lay down our lives for the brethren.</text>
				<references>1Jn 3:16;Eph 3:19; Jn 15:13; 2Co 8:9; 1Jn 4:11; Eph 4:32; Col 3:13; Mk 10:45; 1Pe 2:21; Jn 3:14-15; 1Jn 3:1</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>What things soever the Father doeth, these also doeth the Sone likewise.</heading>
				<text>The LORD giveth wisdom: out of his mouth cometh knowledge and understanding. -I will give you a mouth and wisdom, which all your adversaries shall not be able to gainsay or resist.
                Wait on the LORD: be of good courage, and he shall strengthen thine heart. -My grace is sufficient for thee: fo rmy strength is made perfect in weakness.
                Them that are sanctified by God the Father. -He that sanctifieth and they who are sanctified are all of one: for which cause he is not ashamed to call them brethren.
                Do not I fill heaven and earth? saith the LORD. -The fulness of him that filleth all in all.
                I, even I, am the LORD; and beside me there is no saviour, -This is indeed the Christ; the Saviour of the world.
                Grace, mercy, and peace, from God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ our Saviour.</text>
				<references>Jn 5:19; Pr 2:6;Lk 21:15; Ps 27:14; 2Co12:9; Jude 1; Heb 2:11; Je 23:24; Eph 1:23; Is 43:11; Jn 4:42; Tit 1:4</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='September 30'>
			<morning>
				<heading>He knoweth the way that I take: when he hath tried me, I shall come forth as gold.</heading>
				<text>He knoweth our frame. -He doth not afflict willingly nor grieve the children of men.
                The foundation of God standeth sure, having this seal, The Lord knoweth them that are his. And, Let every one that nameth the name of Christ depart from iniquity.  But in a great house there are not only vessels of gold and of silver, but also of wood and of earth; and some to honour, and some to dishonour.  If a man therefore purge himself from these, he shall be a vessel unto honour, sanctified, and meet for the master's use, and prepared unto every good work.
                He shall sit as a refiner and purifier of silver: and he shall purify the sons of Levi, and purge them as gold and silver, that they may offer unto the LORD an offering in righteousness. -I ...will refine them as silver is refined, ...they shall call on my name, and I will hear them: I will say, It is my people: and they shall say, The LORD is my God.</text>
				<references>Jb 23:10; Ps 103:14; La 3:33; 2Ti 2:19-21; Mal 3:3; Zec 13:9</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Shew me thy ways, O Lord; teach me thy paths.</heading>
				<text>Moses said unto the LORD, I pray thee, if I have found grace in thy sight, shew me now thy way, that I may know thee.  And he said, My presence shall go with thee, and I will give thee rest. -He made known his ways unto Moses, his acts unto the children of Israel.
                The meek will he guide in judgment: and the meek will he teach his way.  What man is he that feareth the LORD? him shall he teachin the way that he shall choose. -Trust in the LORD with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.  In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.
                Thou wilt shew me the path of life: in thy presence is fulness of joy; at thy right hand there are pleasures forevermore. -I will instruct thee and teach thee in the way which thou shalt go: I will guide thee with mine eye. -The path of the just is as the shining light, that shineth more and more unto the perfect day.</text>
				<references>Ps 25:4; Ex 33:12-14; Ps 103:7; Ps 25:9,12; Pr 3:5-6; Ps 16:11; Ps 32:8; Pr 4:18</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 1'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The fruit of the spirit is ...temperence.</heading>
                <text>Every man that striveth for the mastery is temperate in all things.  Now they do it  to obtain a corruptible crown; but we an incorruptible.  I therefore so run, not as uncertainly; so fight I, not as one that beateth the air: but I keep under my body, and bring it into subjection: lest that by any means when I have preached to others, I myself should be a castaway.
                Be not drunk with wine, wherein is excess; but be filled with the Spirit.
                If any man will come afer me, let him deny imself, and take up his cross, and follow me.
                Let us not sleep, as do others; but let us watch and be sober. For they that sleep sleep in the night; and they that be drunken are drunken in the night.  But let us, who are of th eday, be sober. -Denying ungodliness and worldly lusts, we should live soberly, righteously, and godly, in this present world; looking for that blessed hope, and the glorious appearing of the great God and  our Savour Jesus Christ.</text>
				<references>Ga 5:22-23; 1Co 9:25-27; Eph 5:18; Mat 16:24; 1Th 5:6-8; Tit 2:12-13</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 2'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The goat shall bear upon him all their iniquities unto a land not inhabited; and he shall let go the goat in the wilderness.</heading>
                <text>As far as the east is from the west, so far hath he removed our transgressions from us. -In those days, and in that time, saith the LORD, the iniquity of Israel shall be sought for, and there shall be none; and the sins of Juduh, and they shall not be found: for I will pardon them whom I reserve. -Thou wilt cast all their sins into the depths of the sea.  Who is a God like unto thee, that pardoneth iniquity?
				All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all. -He shall bear their iniquities.  Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; because he hath poured out his soul unto death; and he was numbered with the transgressors; and he bare the sin of many, and made intercession for the transgressors. -The Lamb of God, which taketh away the sin of the world.</text>
				<references>Lev 16:22; Ps 103:12; Jer 50:20; Mic 7:19,18; Is 53:6; Is 53:11-12; Jn 1:29</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 3'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Unto him that loved us, and washed us from our sins in his own blood.</heading>
                <text>Many waters cannot quench love, neither can the floods drown it. Love is strong as death. -Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.
				Who his own self bare our sins in his own body on the tree, that we, being dead to sins, should live unto righteousness: by whose stripes ye were healed. -In whom we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, anccording to the riches of his grace.
				Ye are washed, ...ye are sanctified, ...ye are justified in the name of the Lord Jesus, and by the Spirit of our God. -Ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood, an holy nation, a peculiar people; that ye should shew forth the praises of him who hath called you out of darkness into his marvellous light. -I beseech you ...brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable unto God, which is your reasonable service.</text>
				<references>Rev 1:5; Ca 8:7,6; Jn 15:13; 1Pe 2:24; Eph 1:7; 1Co 6:11; 1Pe 2:9; Ro 12:1</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 4'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Mosest wist not that the skin of his face shone while he talked with him.</heading>
                <text>Not unto us, O LORD, not unto us, but unto thy name give glory. -Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, and fed thee? or thirsty, and gave thee drink? -In lowliness of mind let each esteem other better than themselves. -Be clothed with humility.
				[Jesus] was transfigured before them: and his face did shine as the sun, and hiss raiment was white as the light. -All that sat in the council, looking steadfastly on [Stephen], saw his face as it had been the face of an angel. -The glory which thou gavest me I have given them. -We all, with open face beholding as in a glass the glory of the Lord, are changed into the same image from glory to glory, even as by the Spirit of the Lord.
				Ye are the light of the world.  A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid.  Neither do men light a candle, and put it under a bushel, but on a candlestick; and it giveth light unto all that are in the house.</text>
				<references>Ex 34:29; Ps 115:1; Mt 25:37; Php 2:3; 1Pe 5:5; Mt 17:2; Ac 6:15; Jn 17:22; 2Co 3:18; Mt 5:14-15</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 5'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Call upon me in the day of trouble: I will deliver thee, and thou shalt glorify me.</heading>
                <text>Why aret thou cast down, O my soul? and why art thou disquieted within me? hpe thou in God: for I shall yet praise him, who is the health of my countenance, and my God. -LORD, thou hast heard the desire of the humble: thou wilt prepare their heart, thou wilt cause thine ear to hear. -For thou, Lord, art good, and ready to forgive; and plenteous in mercy unto all them that call upon thee.
				Jacob said unto his household, ...Let us arise and go up to Bethel; and I will make there an altar unto God, who answered me in the day of my distress, and was with me in the way which I went. -Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits.
				I love the LORD, because he hath heard my voice and my supplications. Because he hath inclined his ear unto me, therefore will I call upon him as long as I live.  The sorrows of death compassed me, and the pains of hell gat hold upon me: I found trouble and sorrow.  Then called I on the name of the LORD.</text>
				<references>Ps50:15; Ps 42:11; Ps 10:17; Ps 86:5; Gen 35:2-3; Ps 103:2; Ps 116:14</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Yet a little while, (Gr. how little, how little,) and he that shall come will come, and will not tarry.</heading>
				<text>Write the vision, and make it plain upon tables, that he may run that readeth it.  For the vision is yet for an appointed time, but at the end it shall speak, and not lie: though it tarry, wait for it because it will surely come, it will not tarry.
				Beloved, be not ignorant of this one thing, that one day is with the Lord as a thousand years, and a thousand years as one day.  The Lord is not slack concerning his promise, as some men count slackness; but is longsuffering to us ward, not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentence. -Thou, O Lord, art a God full of compassion, and gracious, longsuffering and plenteous in mercy and truth.  -Oh that thou wouldest rend the heavens, that thou wouldest come down.  For since the beginning of the world men have not heard, nor perceived by the ear, neither hath the eye seen, O God, beside thee, what he hath prepared for him that waiteth for him.</text>
				<references>Heb 10:37; Hab 2:2-3; 1Pe 3:8-9; Ps 86:15; Is 64:1,4</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 6'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The Lord God omnipotent reigneth,</heading>
                		<text>I know that thou canst do everything. -The things which are impossible with men are possible with God. -He doeth according to his will in the army of heaven, and among the inhabitants of the earth: and none can stay his hand, or say unto him, What doest thou? -There is none that can deliver out of my hand: I will work, and who shall let it? -Abba, Father, all things are possible unto thee.
				Believe ye that I am able to do this?  They said unto him, Yea, Lord.  Then touched he their eyes, saying, According to your faith be it unto you. -Lord, if thou wilt, thou canst make me clean.  And Jesus put forth his hand, and touched him, saying, I will; be thou clean. -The mighty God. -All power is given unto me in heaven and earth.
				Some trust in chariots, and some in horses: but we will remember the name of the LORD our God. -Be strong and courageous, be not afraid nor dismayed, ...there be more with us than with him.</text>
				<references>Rev 19:6; Job 42:2; Lk 18:27; Da 4:35; Is 43:13; Mk 14:36; Mt 9:28-29; Mt 8:2-3; Is 9:6; Mt 28:18; Ps 20:7; 2Ch 32:7</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 7'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The meek will he teach his way</heading>
        		<text>Blessed are the meek.
            	I returned, and saw under the sun, that the race is not to the swift, nor the battle to the strong, neither yet bread to the wise, nor yet riches to men of understanding, nor yet favour to men of skill. -A man's heart deviseth his way: but the LORD directeth his steps.
            	Unto thee lift I up mine eyes, O thou that dwelleth in the heavens.  Behold as the eyes of servants look unto the hand of their masters, and as the eyes of a maiden unto the hand of her mistress; so our eyes wait upon the LORD our God. -Cause me to know the way wherein I should walk; for I lift up my soul unto thee.
            	O our God, wilt thou not judge them? for we have no might against this great company that cometh against us; neither know we what to do: but our eyes are upon thee.
            	If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.
            	When he, the Spirit of truth, is come, he will guide you into all truth.</text>
				<references>Ps 25:9; Mt 5:5; Ecc9:11; Pr 16:9; Ps 123:1-2; Ps 143:8; 2Ch 20:12; Jas 1:5; Jn 16:13</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
        <day date='October 8'>
			<morning>
				 will not fear what man shall do unto me.<heading></heading>
        		<text>Who shall separate us from the love of Christ?  shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword?  Nay, in all these thinngs we are more than conquerors through him that loved us.
				Be not afraid of them that kill the body, and after that have no more that they can do.  But I will forewarn you whom ye shall fear: Fear him, whicch after he hath killed hath power to cast into hell; yea, I say unto you, Fear him.
				Blessed are they which are persecuted for righteousness' sake; for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.  Blessed are ye, when men shall revile you, and persecute you, and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.  Rejoice, and be exceeding glad; for great is your reward in heaven. -None of these things move me, neither count I my life dear unto myself, so that I might finish my course with joy. -I will speak of thy testimonies ...before kings, and will not be ashamed.</text>
				<references>Heb 13:6; Ro 8:35,37; Lk 12:4-5; Mt 5:10-12; Ac 20:24; Ps 119:46</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>He ...set my feet upon a rock.</heading>
				<text>That Rock was Christ. -Simon Peter ...said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God. ...Upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. -Neither is there salvation in any other: for there is none other name under heaven given among men, whereby we must be saved.
				Full of assurance of faith.  Faith without wavering. -Faith, nothing wavering. ...He that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.
				Who shall separate us from the love of Christ?  shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword?  Nay, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him that loved us.  For I am persuaded, that neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor things to come, nor height, nor depth, nor any other creture, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.</text>
				<references>Ps 40:2; 1Co 10:; Mt 16:16,18; Ac 4:12; Heb 10:22-23; Jas 1:6; Ro 8:35,37-39</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
    <day date='October 9'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Thou art a God ready to pardon, gracious and merciful.</heading>
                <text>The Lord is not slack concerning his promise, as some men count slackness; but is longsuffering to usward, not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance. -The longsuffering of our Lord is salvation.
            	For this cause I obtained mercy, that in me first Jesus Christ might shew forth all longsuffering for a pttern to them which should hereafter believe on him to life everlasting. -Whatsoever things were written aforetime were written for our learninng, that we through patience and comfort of the scriptures might have hope.
            	Despisest thou the riches of his goodness and forbearance and longsuffering; not knowing that the goodness of God leadeth thee to repentance? -Rend your heart, and not your garments, and turn unto the LORD your God: for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and of great kindness, and repenteth him of the evil.</text>
				<references>Neh 9:17; 2Pe 3:9; 1Ti 1:16; Ro 15:4; Ro 2:4; Joel 2:13</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>The words of the Lord are pure words.</heading>
				<text>Thy word is very pure: therefore thy servant loveth it. -The statutes of the LORD are right, rejoicing the heart: the commandment of the LORD is pure, enlightening the eyes. -Every word of God is pure: he is a shield unto them that put their trust in him.  Add thou not unto his words, lest he reprove thee, and thou be found a liar.
      	Thy word have I hid in mine heart, that I might not sin against thee.  I will meditate in thy precepts, and have respect unto thy ways. -Brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever things are honest, whatsoever things are just, whatsoever things are pure, whatsoever things are lovely, whatsoever things are of good report, if there be any virtue and if there be any praise, think on these things. -As newborn babes, desire the sincere milk of the word that ye may grow thereby.
      	We are not as many, which corrupt the word of God: but as of sincerity, but as of God, in the sight of God speak we in Christ. -Nor handling the word of God deceitfully.</text>
				<references>Ps 12:6; Ps 119:140; Ps 19:8; Pr 30:5-6; Ps 119:11; Php 4:8; 1Pe 2:2; 2Co 2:17; 2Co 4:2</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 10'>
			<morning>
				<heading>The whole family in heaven and earth.</heading>
  			<text>One God and Father of all, who is above all, and through all, and in you all. -Ye are the children of God by faith in Christ Jesus. -That in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth; even in him.
				He is not ashamed to call them brethren. -Behold my mother and my brethren?  Whosoever shall do the will of my Father which is in heaven, the same is my brother, and sister, and mother. -Go to my brethren, and say unto them, I ascend unto my Father, and your Father.
			I saw under the altar the souls of them that were slain for the word of God, and for the testimony which they held: ...and white robes were given unto every one of them; and it was said unto them, that they should rest for a little season, until their fellow servants also and their brethren, that should be killed as they were, should be fulfilled. -That they without us should not be made perfect.</text>
				<references>Eph 3:15; Eph 4:6; Gal 3:26; Eph 1:10; Heb 2:11; Mt 12:49-50; Jn 20:17; Rev 6:9-11; Heb 11:40</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>After this manner ...pray ye: Our Father which art in heaven.</heading>
				<text>Jesus ...lifted up his eyes to heaven, and said, Father. -My Father and your Father.
				Ye are all the children of God by faith in Christ Jesus. -Ye have not received the spirit of bondage again to fear; but ye have received the Spirit of adoption, whereby we cry, Abba, Father.  The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God.
				Because ye are sons, God hath sent forth the Spirit of his Son into your hearts, crying, Abba, Father.  Wherefore thou art no more a servant, but a son.
				Verily, verily, I say unto you, Whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, he will give it you.  Hitherto have ye asked nothing in my name: ask and ye shall receive, that your joy may be full.
				I will receive you, and will be a Father unto you, and ye shall be my sons and daughters, saith the Lord Almighty.</text>
				<references>Mt 6:9; Jn 17:1; Jn 20:17; Gal 3:26; Ro 8:15-16; Ga 4:6-7; Jn 16:23-24; 2Co 6:17-18</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 11'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Be not far from me; for trouble is near.</heading>
				<text>How long wilt thou forget me, O LORD? forever? how long wilt thou hoide thy face from me? How long shall I take counsel in my soul, having sorrow in my heart daily? -Hide not thy face far from me; put not thy servant away in anger: thou hast been my help; leave me not, neither forsake me, O God of my salvation.
				He shall call upon me, and I will answer him: I will be with him in trouble; I will deliver him, and honour him. -The LORD is nigh unto all them that call upon him, to all that call upon him in truth.  He will fulfil the desire of them that fear him: he also will hear their cry, and will save them.
				I will not leave you comfortless: I will come to you. -Lo, I am with you alway, even to the end of the world.</text>
				<references>Ps 22:11; Ps 13:1-2; Ps 27:9; Ps 91:15; Ps 145:18-19; Jn 14:18; Mt 28:20; Ps 46:1; Ps 62:1-5</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 12'>
			<morning>
				<heading>God was in Christ, reconciling the world unto himself, not imputing their trespasses unto them.</heading>
        <text>It pleased the Father, that in him should all fulness dwell; and, having made peace through the blood of his cross, by him to reconcile all things unto himself. -Mercy and truth are met together; righteousness and peace have kissed each other.
				I know the thoughts that I think toward you, saith the LORD< thoughts of peace, and not of evil. -Come now, and let us reason together, saith the LORD: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like cromson, they shall be as wool.
			  Who is a God like unto thee, that pardoneth iniquity?
		    Acquaint now thyself with him, and be at peace. -Work out your own salvation with fear and trembling.  For it is God which worketh in you both to will and to do of his good pleasure. -LORD, thou wilt ordain peace for us: for thou also hast wrought all our works in us.</text>
				<references>2Co 5:19; Col 1:19; Ps 85:10; Jer 29:11; Is 1:18; Mic 7:18; Job 22:21; Php 2:12-13; Is 26:12</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Thy kingdom come.</heading>
				<text>In the days of these kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not be left to other people, but it shall break in pieces and consume all these kingdoms, and it shall stand forever. -A stone ...cut out without hands. -Not by might, nor by power, but by my Spirit, saith the LORD of hosts. -The kingdom of God cometh not with observation: neither shall they say, Low here! or, lo there! for, behold, the kingdom of God is within you.
				Unto you it is given to know the mystery of the kingdom of God. So is the kingdom of God, as if a man should cast seed into the ground; and should sleep, and rise night and day, and the seed should spring and grow up, he knoweth not how.  But when the fruit is brought forth, immediately he putteth in the sickle, because the harvest is come.
			  Be ye ...ready: for in such an hour as ye thik not, the Son of man cometh.
		    The Spirit and the bride say, Come.  And let him that heareth say, Come.</text>
				<references>Mt 6:10; Dan 2:44; Dan 2:34; Zec 4:6; Lk 17:20-21; Mk 4:11,26,27,29; Mt 24:44; Rev 22:17</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 13'>
			<morning>
				<heading>From the first day thou didst set thine heart to understatd, and to chasten thyself before thy God, thy words were heard.</heading>
        <text>Thus saith the high and lofty One that inhabiteth eternity, whose name is Holy; I dwell in the high and holy place, with him also that is of a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of humble, and to revive the heart of the contrite ones. -The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit; a broken and contrite heart, O God, thou wilt not despise. -Though the Lord be high, yet hat he respect unto the lowly: but the proud he knoweth afar off. -Humble yourselves therefore under the mighty hand of God, that he may exalt you in due time. -God resisteth the proud, but giveth grace unto the humble.  Submit yourselves therefore to God.
				Thou, Lord, art good, and ready to forgive; and plenteous in mercy unto all them that call upon thee.  Give ear, O Lord, unto my prayer; and attend to the voice of my supplications.  In the day of my trouble I will call upon thee: for thou wilt answer me.</text>
				<references>Dan 10:12; Is 57:15; Ps 51:17; Ps 138:6; 1Pe 5:6; Jas 4:6-7; Ps 86:5-7</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Thy will be done in earth, as in heaven.</heading>
				<text>Understanding what the will of the Lord is.
				It is not the will of your Father which is in heaven, that one of these little ones should perish.
			  This is the will of God, even your sanctification. -That he no longer should live the rest of his time in the flesh to the lusts of men, but to the will of God. -Of his own will begat he us with the word of truth: wherefore lay apart all filthiness.
			  Be ye holy; for I am holy. -[Jesus] said, Whosoever shall do the will of God, the same is my brother, and my sister, and mother. -Whosoever heareth these sayings of mine, and doeth them, I will liken him unto a wise man, which built his house upon a rock: and the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell not; for it was founded upon a rock. -The world passeth away, and the lust thereof: but he that doeth the will of God abideth forever.</text>
				<references>Mt 6:10; Ep 5:17; Mt 18:14; 1Th 4:3; 1Pe 4:2; Jas 1:18,21; 1Pe 1:16; Mk 3:34-35; Mt 7:24-25; 1Jn 2:17</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 14'>
			<morning>
				<heading>Christ both died, and rose, and revived, that he might be Lord of both the dead and the living.</heading>
        <text>It pleased the LORD to bruise him; he hath put him to grief: when thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin, he shall see his seed, he shall prolong his days, and the pleasure of the LORD shall prosper in his hand.  He shall see of the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied: by his knowledge shall my righteous servant justify many; for he shall bear their iniquities. -Ought not Christ to have suffered these things, and to enter into his glory? -We thus judge, that if one died for all, then were all dead: and that he died for all, that they which live should not henceforth live unto themselves, but unto him which died for them, and rose again.
				Let all the house of Israel know assuredly, that God hath made that same Jesus, whom ye have crucified, both Lord and Christ. -Who verily was foreordained before the foundation of the world, but was manifest in these last times for you, who by him do believe in God.</text>
				<references>Ro 14:9; Isa 53:10-11; Lk 24:26; 2Co 5:14-15; Ac 2:36; 1Pe 1:20-21</references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading>Give us this day our daily bread.</heading>
				<text>I have been young, and now am old; yet have I not seen the righteous forsake, nor his seed begging bread. -His bread shall be given him; his waters shall be sure. -The ravens brought him bread and flesh in the morning, and bread and flesh in the evening; and he drank of the brook.
				My God shall supply all your need according to his riches in glory by Christ Jesus. -Be content with such things as ye have: for he hat said, I will never leave thee, nor forsake thee.
			  He humbled thee, and suffered thee to hunger, and fed thee with manna, ...that he might make thee know that man doth not live by bread only, but by every word that proceedeth out of the mouth of the LORD doth man live. -Jesus said unto them, Verily, verily, I say unto you, Moses gave you not that bread from heaven; but my Father giveth you the true bread from heaven.  For the bread of God is he which cometh down from heaven, and giveth life unto the world.  Then said they unto him, Lord, evermore give us this bread.</text>
				<references>Mt 6:11; Ps 37:25; Is 33:16 1Ki 17:6; Php 4:19; Heb 13:5; Dt 8:3; Jn 6:32,34</references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 15'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 16'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 17'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 18'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 19'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 20'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 21'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 22'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 23'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 24'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 25'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 26'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 27'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 28'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 29'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 30'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
		<day date='October 31'>
			<morning>
				<heading></heading>
        <text></text>
				<references></references>
			</morning>
			<evening>
				<heading></heading>
				<text></text>
				<references></references>
			</evening>
		</day>
	</days>
</data>
